Contact

8800749199 (Mobile) ajaydubedi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ajaydubedi (LinkedIn)

ajaydubedi.com (Personal) www.ajaydubedi.com/category/ salesforce-blog/ (Blog)

Top Skills

Java

Salesforce.com

Hibernate

Languages

Hindi

English

Bengali

Certifications

Web Component Development

Salesforce Certified Force.com Advance Administrator

Salesforce Certified Administrator

Salesforce Certified Force.com Adminstrator

Certified in Network Management

Ajay Dubedi

Salesforce Certified | Appexchange | Sales, Service & Marketing cloud Consultant

West Delhi, Delhi, India

Summary

Ajay Dubedi is Salesforce Expert. An accomplished Technical Architect, Consultant and Business Analyst with global consultancy experience; designing and implementing solutions for a range of clients. He have assisted and implemented solutions in industries comprising Banking, Health Care, Networking, Education, Telecommunication and Manufacturing.

Due to his technical excellence he is regularly called on as a point person for challenging technical solutions. He is passionate about passing on technical knowledge amongst his peers and this knowledge and desire to share it with his team has bred an atmosphere of encouragement and mutual advancement.

Possess excellent understanding of the following:

- Strong customer interfacing skills consulting/ advisory capability to understand the customer business paradigm and provide value added solutions.
- SFDC CRM Sales Cloud application capabilities and constraints.
- Great exposure in force.com development best practices.
- SOSL and SOQL, and the SalesForce Security model.
- Extensive experience in Apex Programming, VF pages, Triggers, Workflows, Page Layouts, Roles, Profiles, Reports & Dashboards.
- Architecting and building solutions within the SalesForce Portal.
- Ability to understand the core SFDC Standard APIs and develop customized solutions around them.
- Developing and publishing packages into AppExchange's application.
- Data Migration using Data Loader and CLI for very huge data.
- Integration of Google API's into Salesforce VF page.
- Implementation of Microsoft for Outlook. Sharepoint, Navision ERP, MS Excel and Word.

Experience

CloudAnalogy
Co-Founder & President
May 2016 - Present

New Delhi Area, India

Cloud Analogy Softech is an IT Product & Services company that offers services in the area of Salesforce Customization and Development, Web Designing, Web solution, window solution, Quality assurance. Cloud Analogy Softech continues to forge its vision to be instrumental in making our customers' businesses stronger by providing rich technology competencies, domain expertise, and passion for quality software. The corporate vision is to be an Expert Software partner for our clients while maintaining an openminded, dynamic, and customer-centric approach to delivering cutting-edge solutions.

We are a team of business and development experts offering customized solutions in wide-ranging industries and fields, including education, retail, travel and media. Our products serve many companies with guaranteed quality. Our customized solutions for clients are based on analysis of clients' business requirements, so that the products are of high quality and easy to use. We offer our product development in multiple technologies, Salesforce, Heroku, Node.js, AngularJS, Cloud Technology Strategy, Cloud Computing, Enterprise Architecture, Java, Amazon Web Services and Google Apps, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, JScript etc.

Salesforcexpert Salesforce Expert May 2017 - Present Noida Area, India

I am a Salesforce certified Expert and can help you with Salesforce customization, App development, training or support.

Analog Force Managing Director September 2015 - Present Noida Area, India

I offer online and corporate training for various Salesforce certifications. If anyone is looking for Salesforce training can Contact Me. Till date I trained more than 300+ people in the course like ADM 201, ADM 301, App Builder, DEV 401, DEV 501, Sales cloud & Service cloud consultant, Platform

Developer I and II across the globe. Handled several corporate training for leading MNCs. Actively participating in the Salesforce Success Community.

A new passion of mine has been the creation of my blog www.ajaydubedi.com. Within just over a year, Ajaydubedi.com has come from being a personal blog and turned into one of the most well known and highest traffic Salesforce blogs.

SUMO Scheduler

Vice President of Engineering November 2015 - May 2016 (7 months)

- Was responsible for setting Branch Office in India and hiring Development team, QA team, Accounts and HR Department.
- Was responsible for managing dev team (india-based) to deliver 2-3 releases per year to-spec, on-time, and on-budget.
- My Team was delivering patches monthly for various releases.
- Owned necessary documentation & training materials, including
 Release Notes, Video Tutorials, KnowledgeBase Articles, and Installation /
 Implementation Guides.
- Hosting a daily Scrum Meeting with the SUMO Engineering Team.
- Diligently follow the Discovery, Design, Agile Build, QA, Packaging, and Release process.

Algoworks

Practice Head Salesforce
June 2011 - October 2015 (4 years 5 months)

- Salesforce project implementation
- Integration Architectural services
- Best practice and Governance advice

Tata Consultancy Services

System Engineer

February 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 5 months)

- Provide team leadership
- Development and training
- Work with business and technical stakeholders
- Technologies: Integration, Php, Java, webMethods, Salesforce

Accenture

Software Engineer

May 2009 - February 2010 (10 months)

Salesforce Administration, Testing and Code coverage improvement.

Education

Noida Institute of Engineering and Technology Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science (2005 - 2009)

Kendriya Vidyalaya High School, Science · (2002 - 2004)

Sacred Heart High School Kharagpur WB 10th, Mathematics and Computer Science · (1999 - 2002)